MATJAŽ LOVENJAK

IT ENGINEER



PROFILE

Experienced, practical, and versatile Information Technology Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the manufacturing industry. Lately, I've become very interested in the front-end part of web development. So I've been learning HTML, CSS and JS to give myself a new challenge, and hoping to switch my career to being a web developer.



17.8.1988



Kregarjeva 11, 8250 Brežice



+386 41 741 925



matjaz.lovenjak@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/matjaz-lovenjak



https://github.com/rubuz

EDUCATION

IT Engineer

Šolski center Novo mesto, Short-cycle Higher Vocational College, IT engineering

2013 - 2016

SKILLS

WINDOWS OS IT HARDWARE

MS OFFICE HTML, CSS, JS

WORDPRESS TROUBLESHOOT

TEAMWORK COMMUNICATION

PYTHON GIT

EXPERIENCE

System administrator

2017 - Present

Adria Mobil d.o.o., Novo mesto

Working in an IT department mainly as an endpoint administrator and user support. Frequently interacting with end users in a multi-user organization, where I developed problem solving and communication skills. My job roles and responsibilities are:

- providing dedicated technical support to individual users;
- maintaining records of IT assets, planning for future IT investments and upgrades;
- managing, troubleshooting, licensing, and updating hardware and software assets. Then, documenting these activities and following a strategic approach, per organizational policy;
- ensuring that software systems and feature releases are compatible with the IT infrastructure;
- monitoring system health;
- troubleshooting and fixing issues that compromise system performance or access to an IT service;
- writing Powershell scripts to automate certain IT processes;
- testing software and hardware;
- conducting training programs to bring users up to pace with new software installations or IT system changes.

CNC Machinist

2016 - 2017

Adria Mobil d.o.o., Novo mesto

Producing machined parts by:

- programming, setting up, and operating a computer numerical control (CNC) machine
- maintaining quality and safety standards;
- keeping records
- maintaining equipment and supplies
- · working as a team with engineering
- studding blueprints and making necessary changes in the CNC code
- correcting programs to increase the speed and productivity of the CNC machines.

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- Tech: I enjoy keeping myself updated with the latest consumer tech
- Motorcycles: I like working on my motorcycle and going on trips with it
- Fitness: I enjoy working out at my local gym to stay fit and healthy
- Coffee: I excel at making coffee with different brewing methods
- Gaming: having been a passionate gamer my whole life, I love all kinds of games (PC, console, board)